<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://chensi01.github.io/</id>
    <title>Chensi&apos;s Blog</title>
    <updated>2021-04-12T22:10:28.318Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chensi01.github.io/"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://chensi01.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>Welcome</subtitle>
    <logo>https://chensi01.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://chensi01.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2021, Chensi&apos;s Blog</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[vscode+latex]]></title>
        <id>https://chensi01.github.io/post/vscodelatex/</id>
        <link href="https://chensi01.github.io/post/vscodelatex/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-04-12T22:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>参考：https://blog.csdn.net/qq_28303495/article/details/89848209</p>
<ol>
<li>安装LaTeX Workshop插件</li>
<li>配置
<ol>
<li>打开settings.json</li>
<li>增加配置</li>
<li>重启vscode</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p>增加的配置如下：</p>
<pre><code>   {
    &quot;latex-workshop.latex.recipes&quot;: [{
    &quot;name&quot;: &quot;xelatex&quot;,
    &quot;tools&quot;: [
        &quot;xelatex&quot;
    ]
  }, {
    &quot;name&quot;: &quot;latexmk&quot;,
    &quot;tools&quot;: [
        &quot;latexmk&quot;
    ]
  },
  {
    &quot;name&quot;: &quot;pdflatex -&gt; bibtex -&gt; pdflatex*2&quot;,
    &quot;tools&quot;: [
        &quot;pdflatex&quot;,
        &quot;bibtex&quot;,
        &quot;pdflatex&quot;,
        &quot;pdflatex&quot;
    ]
  }
  ],
  &quot;latex-workshop.latex.tools&quot;: [{
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;latexmk&quot;,
  &quot;command&quot;: &quot;latexmk&quot;,
  &quot;args&quot;: [
    &quot;-synctex=1&quot;,
    &quot;-interaction=nonstopmode&quot;,
    &quot;-file-line-error&quot;,
    &quot;-pdf&quot;,
    &quot;%DOC%&quot;
  ]
  }, {
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;xelatex&quot;,
  &quot;command&quot;: &quot;xelatex&quot;,
  &quot;args&quot;: [
    &quot;-synctex=1&quot;,
    &quot;-interaction=nonstopmode&quot;,
    &quot;-file-line-error&quot;,
    &quot;%DOC%&quot;
  ]
  }, {
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;pdflatex&quot;,
  &quot;command&quot;: &quot;pdflatex&quot;,
  &quot;args&quot;: [
    &quot;-synctex=1&quot;,
    &quot;-interaction=nonstopmode&quot;,
    &quot;-file-line-error&quot;,
    &quot;%DOC%&quot;
  ]
  }, {
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;bibtex&quot;,
  &quot;command&quot;: &quot;bibtex&quot;,
  &quot;args&quot;: [
    &quot;%DOCFILE%&quot;
  ]
  }],
  &quot;latex-workshop.view.pdf.viewer&quot;: &quot;tab&quot;,
  &quot;latex-workshop.latex.clean.fileTypes&quot;: [
  &quot;*.aux&quot;,
  &quot;*.bbl&quot;,
  &quot;*.blg&quot;,
  &quot;*.idx&quot;,
  &quot;*.ind&quot;,
  &quot;*.lof&quot;,
  &quot;*.lot&quot;,
  &quot;*.out&quot;,
  &quot;*.toc&quot;,
  &quot;*.acn&quot;,
  &quot;*.acr&quot;,
  &quot;*.alg&quot;,
  &quot;*.glg&quot;,
  &quot;*.glo&quot;,
  &quot;*.gls&quot;,
  &quot;*.ist&quot;,
  &quot;*.fls&quot;,
  &quot;*.log&quot;,
  &quot;*.fdb_latexmk&quot;
  ],
  }
</code></pre>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to spot a liar]]></title>
        <id>https://chensi01.github.io/post/how-to-spot-a-liar/</id>
        <link href="https://chensi01.github.io/post/how-to-spot-a-liar/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-04-12T12:29:30.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>https://www.ted.com/talks/pamela_meyer_how_to_spot_a_liar</p>
<p>Okay, now I don't want to alarm anybody in this room, but it's just come to my attention that the person to your right is a liar. (Laughter) Also, the person to your left is a liar. Also the person sitting in your very seats is a liar. We're all liars. What I'm going to do today is I'm going to show you what the research says about why we're all liars, how you can become a liespotter and why you might want to go the extra mile and go from liespotting to truth seeking, and ultimately to trust building.</p>
<p>Now speaking of trust, ever since I wrote this book, &quot;Liespotting,&quot; no one wants to meet me in person anymore, no, no, no, no, no. They say, &quot;It's okay, we'll email you.&quot; (Laughter) I can't even get a coffee date at Starbucks. My husband's like, &quot;Honey, deception? Maybe you could have focused on cooking. How about French cooking?&quot;</p>
<p>So before I get started, what I'm going to do is I'm going to clarify my goal for you, which is not to teach a game of Gotcha. Liespotters aren't those nitpicky kids, those kids in the back of the room that are shouting, &quot;Gotcha! Gotcha! Your eyebrow twitched. You flared your nostril. I watch that TV show 'Lie To Me.' I know you're lying.&quot; No, liespotters are armed with scientific knowledge of how to spot deception. They use it to get to the truth, and they do what mature leaders do everyday; they have difficult conversations with difficult people, sometimes during very difficult times. And they start up that path by accepting a core proposition, and that proposition is the following: Lying is a cooperative act. Think about it, a lie has no power whatsoever by its mere utterance. Its power emerges when someone else agrees to believe the lie.</p>
<p>So I know it may sound like tough love, but look, if at some point you got lied to, it's because you agreed to get lied to. Truth number one about lying: Lying's a cooperative act. Now not all lies are harmful. Sometimes we're willing participants in deception for the sake of social dignity, maybe to keep a secret that should be kept secret, secret. We say, &quot;Nice song.&quot; &quot;Honey, you don't look fat in that, no.&quot; Or we say, favorite of the digiratti, &quot;You know, I just fished that email out of my spam folder. So sorry.&quot;</p>
<p>But there are times when we are unwilling participants in deception. And that can have dramatic costs for us. Last year saw 997 billion dollars in corporate fraud alone in the United States. That's an eyelash under a trillion dollars. That's seven percent of revenues. Deception can cost billions. Think Enron, Madoff, the mortgage crisis. Or in the case of double agents and traitors, like Robert Hanssen or Aldrich Ames, lies can betray our country, they can compromise our security, they can undermine democracy, they can cause the deaths of those that defend us.</p>
<p>Deception is actually serious business. This con man, Henry Oberlander, he was such an effective con man British authorities say he could have undermined the entire banking system of the Western world. And you can't find this guy on Google; you can't find him anywhere. He was interviewed once, and he said the following. He said, &quot;Look, I've got one rule.&quot; And this was Henry's rule, he said, &quot;Look, everyone is willing to give you something. They're ready to give you something for whatever it is they're hungry for.&quot; And that's the crux of it. If you don't want to be deceived, you have to know, what is it that you're hungry for? And we all kind of hate to admit it. We wish we were better husbands, better wives, smarter, more powerful, taller, richer -- the list goes on. Lying is an attempt to bridge that gap, to connect our wishes and our fantasies about who we wish we were, how we wish we could be, with what we're really like. And boy are we willing to fill in those gaps in our lives with lies.</p>
<p>On a given day, studies show that you may be lied to anywhere from 10 to 200 times. Now granted, many of those are white lies. But in another study, it showed that strangers lied three times within the first 10 minutes of meeting each other. (Laughter) Now when we first hear this data, we recoil. We can't believe how prevalent lying is. We're essentially against lying. But if you look more closely, the plot actually thickens. We lie more to strangers than we lie to coworkers. Extroverts lie more than introverts. Men lie eight times more about themselves than they do other people. Women lie more to protect other people. If you're an average married couple, you're going to lie to your spouse in one out of every 10 interactions. Now you may think that's bad. It you're unmarried, that number drops to three.</p>
<p>Lying's complex. It's woven into the fabric of our daily and our business lives. We're deeply ambivalent about the truth. We parse it out on an as-needed basis, sometimes for very good reasons, other times just because we don't understand the gaps in our lives. That's truth number two about lying. We're against lying, but we're covertly for it in ways that our society has sanctioned for centuries and centuries and centuries. It's as old as breathing. It's part of our culture, it's part of our history. Think Dante, Shakespeare, the Bible, News of the World.</p>
<p>Lying has evolutionary value to us as a species. Researchers have long known that the more intelligent the species, the larger the neocortex, the more likely it is to be deceptive. Now you might remember Koko. Does anybody remember Koko the gorilla who was taught sign language? Koko was taught to communicate via sign language. Here's Koko with her kitten. It's her cute little, fluffy pet kitten. Koko once blamed her pet kitten for ripping a sink out of the wall. (Laughter) We're hardwired to become leaders of the pack. It's starts really, really early. How early? Well babies will fake a cry, pause, wait to see who's coming and then go right back to crying. One-year-olds learn concealment. (Laughter) Two-year-olds bluff. Five-year-olds lie outright. They manipulate via flattery. Nine-year-olds, masters of the cover up. By the time you enter college, you're going to lie to your mom in one out of every five interactions. By the time we enter this work world and we're breadwinners, we enter a world that is just cluttered with spam, fake digital friends, partisan media, ingenious identity thieves, world-class Ponzi schemers, a deception epidemic -- in short, what one author calls a post-truth society. It's been very confusing for a long time now.</p>
<p>What do you do? Well there are steps we can take to navigate our way through the morass. Trained liespotters get to the truth 90 percent of the time. The rest of us, we're only 54 percent accurate. Why is it so easy to learn? There are good liars and there are bad liars. There are no real original liars. We all make the same mistakes. We all use the same techniques. So what I'm going to do is I'm going to show you two patterns of deception. And then we're going to look at the hot spots and see if we can find them ourselves. We're going to start with speech.</p>
<p>(Video) Bill Clinton: I want you to listen to me. I'm going to say this again. I did not have sexual relations with that woman, Miss Lewinsky. I never told anybody to lie, not a single time, never. And these allegations are false. And I need to go back to work for the American people. Thank you.</p>
<p>Pamela Meyer: Okay, what were the telltale signs? Well first we heard what's known as a non-contracted denial. Studies show that people who are overdetermined in their denial will resort to formal rather than informal language. We also heard distancing language: &quot;that woman.&quot; We know that liars will unconsciously distance themselves from their subject using language as their tool. Now if Bill Clinton had said, &quot;Well, to tell you the truth ... &quot; or Richard Nixon's favorite, &quot;In all candor ... &quot; he would have been a dead giveaway for any liespotter than knows that qualifying language, as it's called, qualifying language like that, further discredits the subject. Now if he had repeated the question in its entirety, or if he had peppered his account with a little too much detail -- and we're all really glad he didn't do that -- he would have further discredited himself. Freud had it right. Freud said, look, there's much more to it than speech: &quot;No mortal can keep a secret. If his lips are silent, he chatters with his fingertips.&quot; And we all do it no matter how powerful you are. We all chatter with our fingertips. I'm going to show you Dominique Strauss-Kahn with Obama who's chattering with his fingertips.</p>
<p>Now this brings us to our next pattern, which is body language. With body language, here's what you've got to do. You've really got to just throw your assumptions out the door. Let the science temper your knowledge a little bit. Because we think liars fidget all the time. Well guess what, they're known to freeze their upper bodies when they're lying. We think liars won't look you in the eyes. Well guess what, they look you in the eyes a little too much just to compensate for that myth. We think warmth and smiles convey honesty, sincerity. But a trained liespotter can spot a fake smile a mile away. Can you all spot the fake smile here? You can consciously contract the muscles in your cheeks. But the real smile's in the eyes, the crow's feet of the eyes. They cannot be consciously contracted, especially if you overdid the Botox. Don't overdo the Botox; nobody will think you're honest.</p>
<p>Now we're going to look at the hot spots. Can you tell what's happening in a conversation? Can you start to find the hot spots to see the discrepancies between someone's words and someone's actions? Now I know it seems really obvious, but when you're having a conversation with someone you suspect of deception, attitude is by far the most overlooked but telling of indicators.</p>
<p>An honest person is going to be cooperative. They're going to show they're on your side. They're going to be enthusiastic. They're going to be willing and helpful to getting you to the truth. They're going to be willing to brainstorm, name suspects, provide details. They're going to say, &quot;Hey, maybe it was those guys in payroll that forged those checks.&quot; They're going to be infuriated if they sense they're wrongly accused throughout the entire course of the interview, not just in flashes; they'll be infuriated throughout the entire course of the interview. And if you ask someone honest what should happen to whomever did forge those checks, an honest person is much more likely to recommend strict rather than lenient punishment.</p>
<p>Now let's say you're having that exact same conversation with someone deceptive. That person may be withdrawn, look down, lower their voice, pause, be kind of herky-jerky. Ask a deceptive person to tell their story, they're going to pepper it with way too much detail in all kinds of irrelevant places. And then they're going to tell their story in strict chronological order. And what a trained interrogator does is they come in and in very subtle ways over the course of several hours, they will ask that person to tell that story backwards, and then they'll watch them squirm, and track which questions produce the highest volume of deceptive tells. Why do they do that? Well we all do the same thing. We rehearse our words, but we rarely rehearse our gestures. We say &quot;yes,&quot; we shake our heads &quot;no.&quot; We tell very convincing stories, we slightly shrug our shoulders. We commit terrible crimes, and we smile at the delight in getting away with it. Now that smile is known in the trade as &quot;duping delight.&quot;</p>
<p>And we're going to see that in several videos moving forward, but we're going to start -- for those of you who don't know him, this is presidential candidate John Edwards who shocked America by fathering a child out of wedlock. We're going to see him talk about getting a paternity test. See now if you can spot him saying, &quot;yes&quot; while shaking his head &quot;no,&quot; slightly shrugging his shoulders.</p>
<p>(Video) John Edwards: I'd be happy to participate in one. I know that it's not possible that this child could be mine, because of the timing of events. So I know it's not possible. Happy to take a paternity test, and would love to see it happen. Interviewer: Are you going to do that soon? Is there somebody -- JE: Well, I'm only one side. I'm only one side of the test. But I'm happy to participate in one.</p>
<p>PM: Okay, those head shakes are much easier to spot once you know to look for them. There're going to be times when someone makes one expression while masking another that just kind of leaks through in a flash. Murderers are known to leak sadness. Your new joint venture partner might shake your hand, celebrate, go out to dinner with you and then leak an expression of anger. And we're not all going to become facial expression experts overnight here, but there's one I can teach you that's very dangerous, and it's easy to learn, and that's the expression of contempt. Now with anger, you've got two people on an even playing field. It's still somewhat of a healthy relationship. But when anger turns to contempt, you've been dismissed. It's associated with moral superiority. And for that reason, it's very, very hard to recover from. Here's what it looks like. It's marked by one lip corner pulled up and in. It's the only asymmetrical expression. And in the presence of contempt, whether or not deception follows -- and it doesn't always follow -- look the other way, go the other direction, reconsider the deal, say, &quot;No thank you. I'm not coming up for just one more nightcap. Thank you.&quot;</p>
<p>Science has surfaced many, many more indicators. We know, for example, we know liars will shift their blink rate, point their feet towards an exit. They will take barrier objects and put them between themselves and the person that is interviewing them. They'll alter their vocal tone, often making their vocal tone much lower. Now here's the deal. These behaviors are just behaviors. They're not proof of deception. They're red flags. We're human beings. We make deceptive flailing gestures all over the place all day long. They don't mean anything in and of themselves. But when you see clusters of them, that's your signal. Look, listen, probe, ask some hard questions, get out of that very comfortable mode of knowing, walk into curiosity mode, ask more questions, have a little dignity, treat the person you're talking to with rapport. Don't try to be like those folks on &quot;Law &amp; Order&quot; and those other TV shows that pummel their subjects into submission. Don't be too aggressive, it doesn't work.</p>
<p>Now we've talked a little bit about how to talk to someone who's lying and how to spot a lie. And as I promised, we're now going to look at what the truth looks like. But I'm going to show you two videos, two mothers -- one is lying, one is telling the truth. And these were surfaced by researcher David Matsumoto in California. And I think they're an excellent example of what the truth looks like.</p>
<p>This mother, Diane Downs, shot her kids at close range, drove them to the hospital while they bled all over the car, claimed a scraggy-haired stranger did it. And you'll see when you see the video, she can't even pretend to be an agonizing mother. What you want to look for here is an incredible discrepancy between horrific events that she describes and her very, very cool demeanor. And if you look closely, you'll see duping delight throughout this video.</p>
<p>(Video) Diane Downs: At night when I close my eyes, I can see Christie reaching her hand out to me while I'm driving, and the blood just kept coming out of her mouth. And that -- maybe it'll fade too with time -- but I don't think so. That bothers me the most.</p>
<p>PM: Now I'm going to show you a video of an actual grieving mother, Erin Runnion, confronting her daughter's murderer and torturer in court. Here you're going to see no false emotion, just the authentic expression of a mother's agony.</p>
<p>(Video) Erin Runnion: I wrote this statement on the third anniversary of the night you took my baby, and you hurt her, and you crushed her, you terrified her until her heart stopped. And she fought, and I know she fought you. But I know she looked at you with those amazing brown eyes, and you still wanted to kill her. And I don't understand it, and I never will.</p>
<p>PM: Okay, there's no doubting the veracity of those emotions.</p>
<p>Now the technology around what the truth looks like is progressing on, the science of it. We know for example that we now have specialized eye trackers and infrared brain scans, MRI's that can decode the signals that our bodies send out when we're trying to be deceptive. And these technologies are going to be marketed to all of us as panaceas for deceit, and they will prove incredibly useful some day. But you've got to ask yourself in the meantime: Who do you want on your side of the meeting, someone who's trained in getting to the truth or some guy who's going to drag a 400-pound electroencephalogram through the door?</p>
<p>Liespotters rely on human tools. They know, as someone once said, &quot;Character's who you are in the dark.&quot; And what's kind of interesting is that today we have so little darkness. Our world is lit up 24 hours a day. It's transparent with blogs and social networks broadcasting the buzz of a whole new generation of people that have made a choice to live their lives in public. It's a much more noisy world. So one challenge we have is to remember, oversharing, that's not honesty. Our manic tweeting and texting can blind us to the fact that the subtleties of human decency -- character integrity -- that's still what matters, that's always what's going to matter. So in this much noisier world, it might make sense for us to be just a little bit more explicit about our moral code.</p>
<p>When you combine the science of recognizing deception with the art of looking, listening, you exempt yourself from collaborating in a lie. You start up that path of being just a little bit more explicit, because you signal to everyone around you, you say, &quot;Hey, my world, our world, it's going to be an honest one. My world is going to be one where truth is strengthened and falsehood is recognized and marginalized.&quot; And when you do that, the ground around you starts to shift just a little bit.</p>
<p>And that's the truth. Thank you.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[《硬派健身》阅读笔记]]></title>
        <id>https://chensi01.github.io/post/lesslessying-pai-jian-shen-greatergreater-yue-du-bi-ji/</id>
        <link href="https://chensi01.github.io/post/lesslessying-pai-jian-shen-greatergreater-yue-du-bi-ji/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-04-11T02:41:18.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="intro当我们在聊健身的时候我们在聊些什么">Intro：当我们在聊健身的时候，我们在聊些什么？</h1>
<h2 id="1变得更好">1.变得更好</h2>
<ul>
<li>环境：人们免不了肤浅、势利、刻薄。尤其是今天，互联网放大了一切细枝末节，所有这一切就像是被放在显微镜下，被公众讨论、嘲笑、奚落。</li>
<li>所以，每个人都希望自己变得更好、看起来更健康，而不仅仅是快乐。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2健身不是目的自己才是目的">2.健身不是目的，自己才是目的</h2>
<ul>
<li>健身的目的：身材不是你健身的目的，快乐也不是健身的目的，甚至健身都不是你的目的。你的目的，是发现你自己，困缚于日常生活中的自己。</li>
<li>与身体的关系
<ul>
<li>初始，我跟我的身体对抗。目的性很强的健身效果很差，不仅身材没有变好，运动对我来说，都变成了一种压力。</li>
<li>过程中，我和身体和解。发现自己身体每一个部位存在的意义，我可以渐渐地了解它们、熟悉它们。健身是自己和自己的身体一起，为了更好的生活去努力。</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="3尊重身体">3.尊重身体</h2>
<ul>
<li>尊重自己的身体，尊重科学，自己去寻找和发现健身中的各种知识和宝藏。</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h1 id="c1什么样的身材是好身材">C1：什么样的身材是好身材？</h1>
<ul>
<li>好身材：富有生命力的身材，瘦而有型。“型”是骨骼和肌肉的形态与搭配，骨骼可能是天生的，肌肉却不是。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="1一切从大肌群训练开始">1.一切从大肌群训练开始</h2>
<ul>
<li>人体的肌肉是由大肌群（胸、背、臀、腿）和小肌群（肩、胳膊、腹、小腿）构成的。人体的骨骼就像一幢房子的基本结构，大肌群就像墙体，保护内脏、填充身体；小肌群更像是窗帘、茶几之类的小装饰，某种程度上更像一种整体风格的延伸。</li>
<li>为什么最应该练胸、背、臀、腿的大肌群？
<ul>
<li>大肌群与体形的关系：大肌群修饰整体体形，是第一眼就能看到的部位，可以塑造一种直观上整体完美的体形。小肌群是只有自己才在乎的微小细节。</li>
<li>减脂增肌角度：从减脂角度看，相对于大肌群，小肌群消耗的热量是微不足道的，在减脂塑身方面效果甚小；对于增肌者来说，也只有大重量、大肌群的训练才能更好地刺激各种激素（睾酮或生长激素等）的分泌。</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>给训练入门者一个诚心诚意的忠告：放弃大多数小肌群训练，从今天起，每天做一次大肌群训练（胸、背、臀、腿）6～10组，搭配核心肌群训练（腹部、下背部）1～3组，最后做HIIT（高强度间歇训练）15到30分钟。不到半年，你就会惊喜地看到自己的改变。</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="2体型和体脂">2.体型和体脂</h2>
<ul>
<li>体重不是关键。相同身高体重但不同体脂，体型差异是巨大的。</li>
<li>肌肉的好处：
<ul>
<li>密度更大，相同重量下体积更小。</li>
<li>肌肉组织的能量消耗更大。</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h1 id="c3什么样的有氧运动最减脂">C3：什么样的有氧运动最减脂？</h1>
<h2 id="1长时间的有氧运动不是减肥的最好方法">1.长时间的有氧运动不是减肥的最好方法</h2>
<ul>
<li>消耗脂肪的同时也在消耗肌肉，直接影响人体的新陈代谢效率。</li>
<li>对体内内分泌起到的作用类似于节食，导致体内瘦素减少，实际上是促使变胖。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2hiit才是普通人减肥塑身的最好选择">2.HIIT才是普通人减肥塑身的最好选择</h2>
<ul>
<li>定义：HIIT（High-intensity Interval Training，高强度间歇训练）。指多次短时间、高强度的运动训练，在每两次高强度运动之间以较低强度的运动或完全休息形成间歇期。简单地说，HIIT就是一种高强度运动与低强度运动间歇交替的训练方式，</li>
<li>特点在于：（1）短时间内运动强度较大，每次都要达到最大或至少接近最大的运动能力。（2）运动时间相对较短，并且可以通过间歇期间的低强度，来避免不适症状的出现。</li>
<li>优点：
<ul>
<li>（1）高强度：持久减脂，刺激生长激素分泌；</li>
<li>（2）间歇：强效减脂，促进脂肪代谢
<ul>
<li>有间歇的运动中，脂肪参与供能的比例更大，燃烧的脂肪也更多。</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>HIIT在某种程度上是无氧肌肉训练和有氧训练的结合，不仅有助于减去总脂肪量、体脂百分比，而且提升了安静时脂肪的氧化率以及总体的新陈代谢。</li>
<li>高强度间歇运动使受试者获得的愉快感要强于中等强度的持续性运动。</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="3如何设计hiit">3.如何设计HIIT</h2>
<ul>
<li>先让身体习惯动起来，再逐步加强。不要给自己设置太多的阻力，或者太多虚幻的梦想。只要你能稳住心态，正确且坚持锻炼，好身材迟早会有的。</li>
<li>肌群参与得越多，燃脂效果就越好。HIIT的一个不成文的特点就是让身体尽可能多地活动起来。</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="31-减脂hiit爬楼梯">3.1. 减脂HIIT：爬楼梯</h3>
<ul>
<li>爬楼梯的燃脂效果好：运动到的股四头肌和臀大肌都是燃脂能力高且塑形能力好的大肌群。爬楼梯在运动方式上，实际非常接近短间歇的无氧训练，所以每次爬楼，还可以带来48到72个小时的持续燃脂。</li>
<li>爬楼梯伤膝盖？
<ul>
<li>真正伤害到膝盖的并非“爬楼梯”，而是“下楼梯”。爬楼梯上去，再乘坐电梯下来。</li>
<li>掌握正确的姿势：使用臀大肌发力&amp;保证重心靠后
<ol>
<li>一次上两个台阶（大腿和上半身之间的髋角更大，对臀部的刺激更大）</li>
<li>背部挺直</li>
<li>膝盖不能超过脚尖</li>
<li>念动合一：心中默念“用臀部发力，用臀部发力，用臀部发力……”</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>HIIT形式，交替三种速度（快速冲刺、较快、一般）爬100层。每周三次，每次半小时。</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="32-塑形hiit">3.2. 塑形HIIT</h3>
<ul>
<li>【跳跃拍手+直膝前踢+俯卧登山】每个动作一分钟，休息10秒，为一组。每次4组，每周3次。</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h1 id="c4塑形的抗阻训练-雕塑身体细节从抗阻开始">C4：塑形的抗阻训练 - 雕塑身体细节，从抗阻开始。</h1>
<p>胸、背、臀、腿）和小肌群（肩、胳膊、腹、小腿</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021 - 影视听FLAG]]></title>
        <id>https://chensi01.github.io/post/2021-ying-shi-ting-flag/</id>
        <link href="https://chensi01.github.io/post/2021-ying-shi-ting-flag/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-03-28T11:48:38.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>BOOKS</p>
<ul>
<li>少有人走的路</li>
<li>笑到最后</li>
<li>爱的艺术️️✔️</li>
<li>亲密关系</li>
<li>浪潮之巅</li>
<li>深度学习推荐系统✔️</li>
</ul>
<p>MOVIES &amp; SHOWS</p>
<ul>
<li>瘦身十律✔️</li>
<li>本杰明巴顿奇事✔️</li>
<li>遗愿清单✔️</li>
<li>活着</li>
<li>教父✔️</li>
<li>年轻气盛</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>